<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Pedro Mas personal webpage</title>
    <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Pedro Mas personal webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedromasb.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LaLiga Santander 2019/2020 data analysis with Qlik Sense</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2022-11-08-liga-santander-2019-2020-data-analysis-with-qlik-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2022-11-08-liga-santander-2019-2020-data-analysis-with-qlik-sense/</guid>
      <description>Every sports and soccer fan ⚽️ has ever thought about how much we would like to have all the statistics of a league or competition at hand so that, beyond consulting them, we can carry out our own research. Imagine being able to analyze the performance of your favorite player or study the correlation between passing accuracy and points scored per team in a couple of seconds.
There are many websites where we can consult the squad of the different teams in a league, the statistics of each player&amp;hellip; but how to unify content that is segmented into hundreds of different URLs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The structure of the universe</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/the-structure-of-the-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/the-structure-of-the-universe/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what the large-scale structure of our universe looks like? Currently, the ΛCDM (Lambda Cold Dark Matter) model is the most widely accepted model for understanding the formation of structures in the universe. According to this model, small density fluctuations in the primordial universe grew exponentially due to inflation, which caused CDM to collapse in the overdense regions forming halos. Then, baryonic matter (&amp;lsquo;ordinary&amp;rsquo; matter) will gravitationally collapse into these CDM halos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why every world map is wrong</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/why-every-world-map-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/why-every-world-map-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how is it possible to represent the Earth on a 2D map? If you haven´t, now is the time.
In fact, every map of the world you have looked at is wrong, or rather distorted. This is the result of the Mercator projection, which is famous for its ability to represent loxodromes (lines crossing all meridians at a constant angle) as straight segments. Objects are distorted because this projection deforms the distances between meridians into parallel lines, increasing their real widht more and more as it approaches the poles, and also enlarges the distance between parallels as it gets closer to the poles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
