<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Pedro Mas personal webpage</title>
    <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Pedro Mas personal webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pedromasb.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Plotting With Python: From Zero to Hero 🚀</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-12-06-interactive-plotting-with-python-from-zero-to-hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-12-06-interactive-plotting-with-python-from-zero-to-hero/</guid>
      <description>Static data reporting is great when we want the user to focus on a specific view or behavior of the data. However, it can be limiting when the data is too complex or when we want to share different perspectives at the same time.
Interactive data sharing enables data discovery, giving users freedom to delve into the data, create their own contexts and discover new patterns and relationships that were not pre-established.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Grid Search For Autoencoder Hyperparameter Tuning</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-05-16-using-grid-search-for-autoencoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-05-16-using-grid-search-for-autoencoder/</guid>
      <description>Finding the optimal combination of hyperparameters can be a tedious task when building a deep learning model. In this context, the grid search tuning technique is one of the most useful for hyperparameter optimization, and is accessible through the GridSearchCV class (documentation) of the scikit-learn package. Thanks to this technique, the user can evaluate the model for each hyperparameter combination throughout the desired parameter space.
In this brief tutorial we will build a deep autoencoder to reconstruct the images provided by the well known MNIST database of handwritten digits, which is available through the tensorflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimensionality Reduction for Data Visualization With Python</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-03-27-dimensionality-reduction-for-data-visualization-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-03-27-dimensionality-reduction-for-data-visualization-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Dimensionality reduction is one of the techniques that is present in the day-to-day work of scientists and data analysts. In this brief tutorial we will explore the use of different dimensionality reduction algorithms in Python for data visualization and exploration.
Using the data provided by the Sunspot Index and Long-term Solar Observations (SILSO) on the monthly mean total sunspot number, we use two of the most popular dimensionality reduction algorithms: T-Distributed Stochastic Neighborhood Embedding (T-SNE) and Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection (UMAP), to &amp;ldquo;take a look&amp;rdquo; at the overall context of a 12-dimensional data set:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Weekend Working at Roque de los Muchachos Observatory</title>
      <link>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-03-09-roque-de-los-muchachos-observatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedromasb.github.io/post/2023-03-09-roque-de-los-muchachos-observatory/</guid>
      <description>This January, I had the great opportunity to work for two nights at the Nordic Optical Telescope (NOT), one of the many telescopes located at Roque de los Muchachos Observatory on La Palma (Canary Islands). Apart from being one of the most renowned observatories in the world, Roque stands out for it unique location. At an altitude of 2396 meters above sea level, the landscape of the Taburiente National Park and the sea of clouds characteristic of La Palma, which is formed due to the exceptional conditions of the island, are truly breathtaking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
